I was guilty of believing this so I want
to tell you the truth right now
there is no such thing as a magic
strategy that wins 100 of the time but
what we can do as Traders is create a
system that can provide us with an edge
that plays out over time it gives us
consistent profits let me tell you a
quick story towards the beginning of my
trading career I decided I was going to
trade just using price action turns out
it didn't work very well I was a break
even Trader I then decided to switch to
the next thing that I knew which was
using moving averages by themselves in
order to trade again Break Even Trader
one day I decided to combine the moving
average that I had Saul performed the
best throughout all of my testing with
the price action strategy I was already
using and from that day forward
everything changed I went from a break
even Trader to someone seeing consistent
profits in his account so in this video
what I want to do is share with you a
trade I took on the Aussie dollar using
this exact setup along with share with
you the exact rules of this trading
setup that way you come away from this
video with a better understanding of how
to use price action in combination with
a very specific moving average in order
to create highly profitable trading
opportunities so if you feel like
learning a new setup today go ahead and
click that like button for me go and
subscribe if you are new and I'll see
you after the intro and disclaimer
foreign
[Music]
the first thing you have to understand
in order to utilize this trading setup
in your own trading is the way price
moves and the specific movement of price
that we're looking for before looking
for a trade and the first thing we're
going to do so that you do understand
that is we're going to go up here to a
whiteboard and I'm going to explain it
before I do I know my voice is a bit
raspy I just got over being sick so take
it easy on me let's go ahead and take a
look though at what we're looking for in
terms of price when we're looking at a
trending Market which is what we're
going to utilize in order to take
advantage of this setup is we're going
to be looking for higher highs and
higher lows followed by another higher
high this is really all I'm looking for
this is what I call a one two three move
and it just consists of a push-up in
price a pullback and then a push-up that
breaks above the previous resistance
this is the very first step of this
strategy and as soon as I see this I
start to look for this setup so the next
step after I see this trending move in
price is I'm going to be looking for
price to then push back down give me a
pullback that comes to this area of
resistance that is a Zone it's not
necessarily one line on the chart we're
gonna be looking at this Zone and this
zone is likely to provide a bounce
higher let me explain why that's the
case whenever price is moving up and we
have a push-up we have sellers that come
into the market right here that's the
reason we get a pullback the buyers are
losing steam sellers are coming in
trying to push price lower so when
buyers Take Back Control the sellers
don't expect that when they take back
control and push higher than the
previous highs that means that buyers
are actually in control because where
buyers gave out last time is no longer
where they're giving out now they're
pushing prices higher and no matter how
many sellers come in the market they
can't stop it so with that being the
case whenever we get a pullback into
this area if you were selling short
let's say those people didn't have a
stop loss in place at all well now they
can get out near Break Even or even at
break even if they were able to go short
at this top so we're catching those
orders of people that were scared that
went short because prices were going
higher and now they're like I'm getting
out of my position when you get out of a
sell position you have to buy and we're
also getting more buyers stepping into
the market so all that equals buying
pressure that more often than not pushes
prices into new highs so again let me
break it down one more time step one of
this strategy is we're looking for a one
two three move which is just a move
followed by a pullback followed by the
break above the resistance level or the
previous swing High we're then waiting
for prices to pull back to the zone of
that previous swing high and that is the
first step of this strategy and
obviously this is for a bullish trade
we'll go over a bearish example later in
the video now let's take a look at this
on some real charts so you can get
better hand to love it what do you see
right here on the Aussie dollar
hopefully you were able to spot this one
two three move we have prices pushing up
to a high pulling back then pushing up
to what a new high does this look
familiar it looks exactly like what I
drew up on the Whiteboard right so we
have a one two three move what's step
number two we're gonna create a Zone
again it's gonna be a Zone I don't have
any specific rules for this but this is
just a Zone where the previous level of
resistance was that was just broken that
previous swing High we have to have a
Zone in there because this is where more
buyers are likely to come into the
market this is also where people that
sold here got really scared as price
pushed up if they didn't have a stop
loss in place this is their chance to
get out at or near break even so if they
had a sell trade on they have to buy in
order to get out of that sell trade
which is going to automatically push
prices higher when you combine that with
more buyers coming into the market
that's when we can see moves that push
up into brand new highs so so the first
two steps of this strategy are already
in place here on the Aussie dollar and
now that you know the price action side
of things I'm going to go ahead and let
you in on the specific moving average
that I combine with this type of trading
in order to create some highly
profitable trading opportunities the
moving average I use for this trading
setup is probably one of the most widely
used moving averages in trading which
may be why it works so well as a level
of support so simply put it is the 50
period exponential moving average you
can find that just by going to
indicators typing in exponential if you
can figure out how to spell that it's
tough for me and then it'll be the top
one that says moving average exponential
apply that to your chart once you do
you'll just need to go into the settings
of that indicator and you'll go to
inputs and type in 50 for length that's
all you need to mess with just change
the length to 50 then you will have a 50
period exponential moving average on
your chart which is the Blue Line you
see on my chart now so so in combination
with the price action setup you have
already learned that we've already
talked about utilizing this one two
three move and the buying pressure
coming in on the pullback to the
previous resistance this strategy by
itself can work but again when I was
using this by itself I was like a break
even Trader I wasn't making money I
wasn't losing money when I decided to
combine this with price must be bouncing
off of the 50 EMA as well as an added
condition that's when I initially
started to make profits as a Trader so
with that being the case this is a third
condition if you've been around the
channel for a while you know how I like
to create and utilize strategies that is
through an acronym I call CEST
c-e-s-t which stands for conditions my
entry reason my stop loss and my target
so for this specific trading setup the
conditions are our one two three move
and the pullback
and this pullback also needs to be
coming into the 50 period exponential
moving average now I have very specific
rules of when I count this 50 period
moving average as support as long as
candles have been above the 50 period
moving average and are still touching
the moving average I count it as support
let me give you an example of what would
not count as support if we have the
moving average continuing and we have a
candle that does something like this but
we're still touching the moving average
we've closed below it let's say this
candle is red but we're still touching
the moving average then I still count
the moving average as support in that
specific case here is when I stop
counting the moving average is support
if we have a candle that closes below
the moving average and also does not
touch the moving average at all at that
point I no longer count the moving
average as a support level and I move on
to other currency Pairs and try to find
another trade so this is the point when
I stop counting it as support felt like
that was a detail that I needed to share
so let's go over this one more time we
already have now the conditions for this
entire trading setup we have our price
action that we've talked about the one
two three move with the pullback we have
the condition of price needs to be
touching and coming off of the 50 period
exponential moving average so now we
have all the conditions met for this
trading setup what's the next step if
we're going by our acronym of cesd then
that would be our entry it's very simple
for me the entry is buying pressure
buying pressure can come in many forms
Candlestick patterns like a engulfing
bar or a hammer Candlestick for bad
trades a close above candle a candle
just with a long Wick to the bottom and
a really big green bar would be an
example of buying pressure when you go
back test this feel free to back test
multiple entries all at once or multiple
entries separately but make sure you're
really specific about those entries you
want to make sure it's just engulfing
candles and that's what you're looking
for and it's super specific you have
rules for those candles because one of
the leading causes of inconsistency in
Traders is that they don't have specific
rules for an entry so be sure you have
specific rules for that I just call it
buying pressure and I have rules for
what I count as buying pressure one of
those rules I just told you it is a long
Wicked candle with a large green body so
this candle right here just utilizing
this Candlestick pattern on top of what
you've already learned as the entire
setup is my actual entry this
Candlestick once it closes is when I
actually press the buy button for this
specific trade so where are we in the
acronym now we have C taken care of we
have our entry taken care of what's next
we're going to need to look for our stop
loss you need really specific rules for
this as well in order to stay consistent
to a trading strategy so let's create
consistent rules for a stop loss for me
that's going to be just below our entry
candle on this specific trade this is
exactly where my stop loss was you'll
see that in just a second and after we
look for a stop loss c e now we have S
all these are checked off we need to
know where we're getting out if we're
right our stop loss means oh I was
wrong about that trade cool let me get
out my risk Management's on point I only
lose one percent maybe two percent of my
account I'm cool with that it was worth
the risk to take that trade but
where are we getting out of a right
that's something we need to determine as
well for me that area is normally the
next level of resistance price will hit
in the uptrend so if we're in an uptrend
we've already made our one two three
move the likely scenario is that we
break into new highs Above This high if
we do that what's the next level price
is going to see resistance at well it's
the next level of resistance price has
so with that being the case that is
where I put my target now an important
note here is once I hit about a 1.4 to 1
reward to risk ratio on these trades on
this exact setup I do normally move my
stop loss from where it is to break even
right at the 1.4 to 1 and then I just
let the position ride to that next level
of resistance which is exactly what I
did on the specific trade if I hit play
you'll see that price did in fact push
up high enough to hit our targets and we
got out just in time right before the
crash of the Aussie dollar now I'm going
to go over a bearish example of this as
well but before I do I want to show you
that I did actually place this trade so
if you look to my left I think or to my
right whichever way you'll see a
screenshot of the email analysis I sent
out to everyone involved in the TTC
Forex University I send these trades out
two to five times a week if that's
something you're interested in getting
involved in it'll be the top Link in the
description the university includes a
full University style course meant to
take you from beginner to Advanced as a
Trader along with that it includes these
email analysis trades a few times a week
of Trades I'm actually placing based on
what you're learning inside of the
university and on top of that it
includes priority coaching support which
is me answering any trading related
questions you have personally to ensure
that your journey from wherever you are
to profitable trading is as smooth as
possible again that's linked at the top
of the description or go to
www.tdcfxuniversity.com if not that's
completely fine too let's take a look at
a bearish example of this setup right
now take a look at the screen and see if
you can spot the bearish trade now
so hopefully you were able to spot all
of this but at the moment we have a one
two three move on the euro dollar this
move is coming in like one two three
after the one two three move one two
three where are we looking for possible
trades at the previous level of support
and by the way if it's a level that's
been tested multiple times that makes it
an even more accurate trading
opportunity so at this point we have our
one two three price action move do we
have a pullback one two three the
pullback is coming into the previous
level of support so yes we have a
pullback too what's the next step we're
gonna be creating a Zone in our previous
level of support
just like that and we also need what to
be happening
we also even with the pullback coming
into the structure level right even with
that we need it to be aligning and also
pushing off of the 50 EMA this is for a
bearish example we need to be pushing
off to the downside obviously we're
trying to go short here we're selling
the market so do we have that in this
example we zoom in right here this
Candlestick touches our Zone and also
comes off of the 50 EMA so yes we have a
good example of that here now we have
the conditions met for this strategy
what's next what is the entry selling
pressure for a selling trade instead of
buying pressure like a bot trade was for
a short example or a selling trade we're
going to be looking for selling pressure
and the way we're doing that is with
this candle right here we have a
shooting star candle with a really long
Wick to the top side that closes below
the previous candle so with that being
the case we have all we need to actually
enter this trade so that specific candle
would be my entry reason I would go
ahead and enter on the close of that
candle I would go right above the candle
or right above the Zone probably in this
case and I'd be looking at the next
level of structure I think I already
have it pointed out yeah I'd be looking
at the next level of structure for my
targets moving the stop loss to break
even at a round of 1.4 to 1 reward to
risk ratio let's see how this specific
trade plays out
we push down push up a bit and then
eventually do in fact come down to hit
those targets so this would be a good
example
of a bearish version of this exact
trading setup so I just did an
experiment and the results were way
different than I expected I blasted out
an email to our entire email list which
is thousands of Traders asking them what
their number one issue in their trading
was
I was expecting an answer somewhat
similar to I don't have a strategy
what we got back from that was something
way different I actually had my
assistant write out all the answers into
an Excel spreadsheet which
bless her heart because that was so many
emails had to be a lot of work but we
then organized them from the most
popular answer to the least popular
answer the most popular answer by far
was they had a problem staying
disciplined and sticking to one trading
strategy so I know that I just showed
you an entire trading strategy right and
I know I showed you two winning trades
but the reality of trading is that you
are not gonna win every trade the
strategy I just showed you will have
losses and even have losing streaks and
professional Traders have the ability to
continue trading a strategy through
losses and through losing streaks
whereas ninety percent of Traders cannot
find a way to do that so right now what
I want to do is give you three things
that I used in my own personal trading
in order to master my trading mindset
and to continue staying disciplined to a
trading strategy through losing streaks
or drawdowns but first let's talk about
the two things that matter when it comes
to discipline those two things are and
imagine them being on like a
teeter-totter I don't know if that's the
word don't make fun of me imagine them
being kind of on a scale right the two
things are fear and uncertainty and
confidence and belief these two things
are what determine how disciplined
you're going to be to your trading
strategy to your entire trading plan so
the Practical step to take is to try to
increase belief and confidence and
decrease fear and uncertainty so the
first way that I did that was by
starting to back test my trading
strategies so back testing is not sexy
it's not something most people want to
do but if you think about it it's
something that can decrease uncertainty
because you're seeing something work in
the past through drawdowns and it's
something that can increase your
confidence and increase your belief in a
specific strategy let me give you an
example of this if one of your buddies
came up to you and said hey dude I went
horseback riding with Drake yesterday
you'd probably be pretty skeptical and
probably think that didn't actually
happen but what if you were there and
you saw him go horseback riding with
Drake at that point you would believe it
back testing is the same way I just told
you a strategy and no matter how much
you trust me you should still go see it
for yourself you could trust that friend
like crazy that told you you went
horseback riding with Drake that's still
a pretty steep ask for you to believe
that he did it without having any proof
without seeing it so what you need to do
is go back to the trading strategy
because that's similar to you seeing it
happen yourself when you back test
you'll be able to see the trading
strategy that you're going to trade this
one specifically if that's what you
choose go through losing streaks and
drawdowns and come out the other side of
them still being profitable so number
one is back test your trading strategies
now there's a link in the description
and on the screen to a full beginner's
training course that I did that's
absolutely free free and it'll walk you
through the back testing process check
that out if you'd like to number two is
risk management so whenever we're trying
to decrease fear and decrease
uncertainty and increase belief in
confidence this mostly goes into fear
and confidence in order to raise
confidence what if you were to lose less
money on a trade
you would definitely fear it less right
if you're risking 100 of your account
you're going to be in loads of fear
you're going to just be completely
emotional about that trade but what if
you're only risking one percent of your
account now that fear is decreasing and
as that fear decreases your confidence
and your belief is going to naturally
Rise Again imagine these things on a
scale so tip number two is going to be
to use a proper risk management plan now
I can't tell you what to risk because
that's not up to me you need to decide
your own risk tolerance but if you use a
proper risk management plan again it can
kind of move those skills further
towards you being confident and having
belief in your full trading plan and
decrease the fear and uncertainty that
you have through the process of risking
less money on the trades that you place
and the third and final way to increase
your belief and increase your confidence
and decrease that uncertainty and fear
is going to be through experience now I
don't necessarily could suggest doing
this with a real account but if you want
to start a super tiny account and
experience your full trading plan now
this comes after creating a full trading
plan you already have a trading plan you
already have a strategy that you've back
tested and seen that it's profitable and
seen it go through drawdowns and come
out profitable on the other side you
already have a risk management plan that
you're sticking to now is when you can
start to have experience in order to
increase belief and confidence and
decrease the uncertainty and fear that
experience can be done one of two ways
you can either do this for a couple of
months with a tiny account or if you
don't want to risk any money at all
while you're going through this process
you can just do this on a practice
account on a demo account you can take
that full strategy you've already tested
along with the risk management plan that
you've decided to use and use those
things in real markets to gain
experience if you do this over the
course of 60 to 90 days and you see that
in that small account or in that demo
account you come out profitable that is
going to do a major amount to increase
your confidence and belief and decrease
uncertainty and fear and what we're
attempting to do imagine these scales is
get uncertainty and fear all the way
down and belief and confidence all the
way up but if we can do that then you
will no longer have an issue switching
strategies changing your risk management
moving your stop loss all the things
that happen in the six inches between
your ears will be fixed if you can do
those three things don't forget to check
out our completely free beginners course
which is linked in the description and
you can catch it on the link you see on
the screen right now if you're ready for
some more advanced training feel free to
check out the details of the TTC 4-H
University we currently have some space
in that program but it normally runs out
pretty quickly it's the top Link in the
description I really hope you got value
out of today's video if you did be sure
to click that like button be sure to
subscribe if you are new leave me a
comment if you made it all the way to
the end my voice is completely gone so I
am done I'll catch you in the next video
season soon